Okello Michael Onyoin

M

Junior Software Engineer

moonyoin@gmail.com

(+254)799554223

(+256)774350388

onyoin.com/wordpress

Qwetu Wilson View

Michael Onyoin

in

Personal Profile

I am a hardworking and committed person who has developed needed skills and knowledge through the study of Computer Science at an undergraduate level and side internship work experience, exceptional communication skills and use of general computer programming languages such as Html, CSS, JS, Python, MySQL, Kotlin, Java, PHP and many others. Along with skills to use computer apps like Microsoft PowerPoint, Excel etc. I seek to learn and deliver positive change to your organization and contribute to its growth and success.

Date of Birth: 14/02/2001

Sex: Male

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Informatics and Computer Science (BICS)

Strathmore University, Nairobi

07/2020 - 06/2024

Average Grade: 65.59

Uganda Advanced Certificate of Education (UACE)

St. Mary's Secondary School Kitende

05/2018 - 11/2019

Points: 12 (PCM)

Uganda Certificate of Education (UCE)

St. Mary's College Kisubi

04/2013 - 11/2017

Aggregates: 20

Primary Leaving Education (PLE)

Greenhill Academy

02/2006 - 11/2012

Aggregates: 6

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer Intern

National Information Technology Authority of Uganda (NITA-U) | 01/2023 - 03/2023

During my three-month intern period at NITA-U, I was majorly involved in IT Change Management that meant IT teams responding to service interruptions across Uganda and providing service restoration. This involved a lot of Service Desk jobs. I was also involved in IT Certification of IT companies in Uganda through NITA-U.

Intern

Help Africa Foundation | 02/2022 - 04/2022

During my two-month intern period at Help Africa I learnt what it means to be a contributing member to the community through charitable work. I personally helped record interviews and take photos of children to post on social media requesting funding contributions from the public while verifying their poor background.

PROJECTS

 A Blockchain System to Secure Voter Registration Using

SKILLS

PROFESSIONAL

Web development

Android app development

Database Administration

Penetration testing

Communication skills

Interpersonal skills

IT Change Management skills

Certificates

- CCNA Network and routing essentials
- CISCO IT Fundamentals
- Cyber Security: White-Hat Ethical Hacking (Progress: 64%)

LANGUAGE

English

Fingerprint Data. (August 2023 - January 2024)

This project incorporates a web app (React) or Android app with Blockchain to build a secure system to store voter registry information.

Site: https://votechain-xi.vercel.app/

An Online Pharmacy System. (April 2022 – July 2022)

This project provides an online platform for patients to buy, order and get their drugs delivered to them easily.

REFERENCES

Strathmore ICS Lecturer **Daniel Machanje**

Contact: +254 725 622840

Email: dmachanje@strathmore.edu

Programs Manager of Help Africa

Mariam Mirembe

Contact: +256 782 855476

Email: mariam@helpafrica.dk

Service Desk Supervisor

Arthur Munanura

Contact: +256 772 186449

Email: arthur.munanura@nita.go.ug